大西洋帝国
第五季 第一集
做人要诚实 孩子们
"Be honest and true,boys!
凡事都要真诚 孩子们
Whatever you do,boys,
要铭记一生
Let this be your motto through life."
从今以后 为此努力
"Both now and forever,be this your endeavor,
当正邪交锋之际
When wrong with the right is at strife.
至真至善之人 总是弥足珍贵
The best and the truest; Alas! Are the fewest;
努力做这样的人
But be one of these if you can.
尽职尽责
In duty,ne'er fail;
这会让你受益匪浅
you will find 'twill avail you,
终生受用
And bring its reward when a man.
生活的海洋充满波浪...
Don't think life plain sailing...
充满艰险
there's danger of failing,
尽管未来貌似光明...
though bright the futures seem to be...
但尊严 努力 真诚待人
but bright honor and labor and truth to your neighbor
会带你平安度过人生之海
will bear you safe over life's seas."
准将 准将
Commodore! Commodore!
求您了 再扔啊
Here,please. Throw another.
先生
Mister!
大西洋城 一八八四年
准将先生 给我扔一个吧
Mr. Commodore. Throw one to me.
女士们 先生们 阳光明媚的夏天开始了
Now commences our sun-kissed summer, ladies and gentlemen.
我们将金币洒在海上
We sprinkle the sea with gold
大海给我们百倍的回赠
and the sea gives it back to us 100 fold.
这是我们这片有福之地的荣耀
That is the glory of this blessed strand
这就是大西洋城
that we call Atlantic City.
-再扔啊 -准将先生
-Throw it! -Mr. Commodore!
-在这 -你们还想要吗
-Here! -You want some more,do you?
-我想要钱  -扔过来啊
-I want to have the money! -Come on,over here!
这就对了
Now that's how you get yourself along.
庆典完毕 饮酒开始
The ceremony concludes and libations await
科纳酒店老板请客
compliments of the Corner Hotel.
我们走吧
To the wagons,ho!
看我捡的
Look what I got.
快看 看我找到的
Over here. Look what I found.
我们游了多长时间
How long was that?
我憋气比你久
I can hold my breath longer than you.
-别吹了  -就是
-No,you can't. -Yes,I can.
古巴 哈瓦那 一九三一年
摇啊 摇啊
Shake it. Shake it.
我讨厌这样
I hate this.
卖古巴鸡尾酒的地方
It sells mojitos.
那混蛋在哪
Where is the goddamn son of a bitch?
他会现身的
He'll show.
迟到四天了
Four days late?
你说过你喜欢古巴
You said you liked Cuba.
你为何觉得我不喜欢了
What makes you think I don't?
刚才的谈话
This conversation.
我只想尽快完成交易
I just want the deal to be nailed down.
你相信我吗
Trust me or not?
当然
Of course I do.
那就闭嘴 跳舞吧
Then shut up and dance.
顾客们都看着呢
My customers are watching.
你的枪鱼来了 开心了吧
There's your marlin. You happy now?
我吗
Me?
我一直很开心
I'm always happy.
温德尔
Wendell.
哈瓦那欢迎你
Bienvenidos a la Habana.
快 快
Move it,move it.
排好队
Line up,line up.
下车
Unload it.
下来 犯人
Get moving,stripeys.
拿工具 干活
Get your tools and get to work.
-快  -快 快 拿起来
-Get running. -Let's go. Let's go. Pick it up.
快 犯人
Get running,stripeys.
这不是派对 快干活
This ain't no party. Come on. Work.
快
Get running.
都给我快点
Y'all keep moving. Let's go.
-别拖拖拉拉的  -快走
-Wake up,wake up. -Pick up your feet. Let's go.
快 快走
Come on,boys. Step up.
给我下来 犯人
I said get running,stripey.
快走 快
Pick up your feet. Let's go.
你耳朵聋啊 快走
You heard me,boy.
快 犯人 快走
Come on,stripey,let's go.
给我快点
Keep moving.
去砍树 快
Hope that tree chops up! Let's go!
带他们过来
Bring 'em here.
快走 犯人
Let's go,stripeys.
快走
Pick it up.
快
Move it.
加把劲
Put your back in it.
我妻子特别想来的
My wife was desperate to come.
她不能和你一起来 真是遗憾 参议员
Aw,shame she couldn't join you,Senator.
"总统"味道如何
How's the Presidente?
这叫"总统"吗 爽极了
That's what this is called? Damn refreshing.
待会尝尝巴卡第酒
Wait till you try the one at Bacardi's.
-他给你倒...  -安兰酒
-He'll pour out the... -Anejo.
你就会发现 名不虚传
You'll see what the fuss is about.
是的 实地考察很重要
Well,it's important to learn the facts on the ground.
威尔克森怎么了
What happened with Wilkerson?
分享一下吧
Anything you can share?
大工程师把自己逼入窘境
The Great Engineer has backed himself into a corner.
威尔克森在报告里全说了
Wilkerson lays it all out in the report.
沃尔斯特禁酒令 长达11年
11 years of Volstead
结果呢...
and all they've managed to achieve is...
你也清楚
you're as aware as anyone.
出于好意
Good intentions.
却没法执行的法案
Unenforceable law.
给您"总统"一杯
A Presidente for you.
免费
It's all on the house.
250亿美元 由于经济危机 灰飞烟灭了
25 billion up in smoke since the crash.
失业率高达16%
16% unemployment.
每年9亿美元的酒税和经营税
900 million a year in liquor taxes
政府拿不到了
and licenses the government isn't getting.
我看 全国人民都该借酒消愁了
You ask me,the whole damn country could use a drink.
胡佛会主张废除法案吗
Will Hoover advocate repeal?
他跟禁酒的人一起上台 就得一起下台
He rode in with the drys,he'll have to ride out with them.
你觉得他会吗
You think he will?
会什么 参加1932年竞选吗
Will he what? Run in '32?
你觉得他会输掉竞选吗
Do you think he'll lose?
随便聊聊而已 行吗
This is all just exploratory,understood?
宪法修正案不会被推翻
Constitutional amendments don't get overturned.
你的有些朋友可不这么想
You have friends who believe otherwise.
那些人 往往如愿以偿
Men like that tend to get what they want.
你也说过
You said it yourself,
有益于国家 就有益于你我
good for the country,good for you and me.
他很寡言
He doesn't talk much.
我喜欢他这点
That's what I like about him.
要清楚
Let's just be clear.
你过去的一些问题
Certain issues regarding your past
阻碍着事情的进展
make moving forward tricky.
我不懂你的意思
I'm not sure what you mean.
我得详细说明吗
Do I have to spell it out?
你可不清白
Your hands aren't the cleanest.
说实话 我确实被捕入狱过
I won't lie. I have been arrested and convicted.
1923年 我在华盛顿联合车站
1923,I bought a pint of Old Granddad
买了一品脱老爷酒
in Union Station in Washington DC.
交了5美元罚款
I paid a $5 fine
在监狱蹲了一晚
and I spent the night in jail.
此事一直困扰着我
It's haunted me ever since.
温德尔 美国是人们可以改过自新的地方
Wendell,if America's not about starting over,
不然 谁会有希望呢
where's the hope for any of us?
参议员 我听说您是外贸专家
Senator,I hear you're a bit of an expert on foreign trade.
我是参议院附属委员会成员
I'm on the Senate subcommittee.
那位小姐
Well,that young lady,
非常热衷这个话题
she is very interested in the subject.
您能和她分享一下经验吗
Would you be willing to share some of your experience?
纽约市
谁知道昨晚我做了什么
Who knows what I did last night?
谁知道
Anybody?
罗翰小姐
Miss Rohan?
我...
Did I...
跟你提过什么事吗
mention anything to you?
你打算去看个"电影" 班尼特先生
I believe you intended to see a "Fillum," Mr. Bennett.
没错
That's exactly right.
我去看"电影"了
I went to a "Fillum,"
你的发音魅力十足
as you charmingly pronounce it,
和我的爱人劳拉一起去看的
with my beloved spouse Laura,
我孩子的母亲
the mother of my children,
因为人生在世 不能只想着钱
because life is not just about dollars and cents.
不是吗
Is it?
没错 先生
No,sir.
我看了电影"满城风雨"
Saw "The Front Page."
新闻业的喜剧
Lively comedy about the newspaper game.
我非常喜欢这部电影
Enjoyed it tremendously.
先前的动画...
The cartoon beforehand...
米老鼠被遗弃到荒岛上
Mickey Mouse cast away on a desert island.
想象一下 那小东西在岛上狂欢...
Just imagine the hijinks that little...
有人看过吗
anyone seen it?
那你就知道我的意思
Then you know what I'm talking about.
猩猩 跳舞的海豹 小虎仔
Gorilla,dancing seals,baby tiger.
在某一刻 米老鼠找到一架钢琴
At one point,Mickey finds a piano...
这不重要
not important.
重要的是
What is important...
米老鼠锲而不舍
he doesn't give up.
在困境中尽力而为 保持乐观
He makes the best of the situation. He stays cheerful.
最终...
And in the end...
最终怎样
what happens in the end?
米老鼠坐着海龟离开了荒岛
He sails away on a turtle?
坐着海龟离开了荒岛
Sails away on a turtle!
看到没 朋友们
You see,friends?
不要被唱反调的人击垮
Don't let the naysayers get you down.
这个国家是强大的 市场是强大的
The country is strong. The market is strong.
康纳 古尔德公司也是强大的
Conors & Gould is strong.
如今是赚钱良机
It is a grand time to make some money.
别紧张 一切都会没事的
Oh,no,no. Everything's gonna work out fine.
修修吧
Fix this?
穿一下 再穿一下
Cross and cross again.
看到没 这叫平结
See? It's called a reef knot.
你试试
You try.
穿一下 再穿一下
Cross and cross again.
他们在屋里吗
They inside?
在
Yeah.
她好热
She's real hot.
能感觉到
You can feel it.
他在哪
Where is he?
在港湾
On the bay.
放下
Leave that.
过来吧
Come on,now.
伊莱
Eli.
妈妈可能需要我们
Mom might need us.
关门
Close the door.
女士们穿什么了
What were the ladies wearing?
一位戴着黄色软帽
One was in a sort of yellow bonnet
穿着绿裙 绿外套
and green skirt and green jacket about to here.
那是晒太阳
It's called a bask.
你吃过东西了吗 伊诺克
Did you eat something,Enoch?
吃过了 有位款爷
Yes. There was a swell.
要去站台 我帮他拎包
He was off to the station so I carried his bags.
他给我买了牡蛎
He bought me oysters.
还有冷面包和糖浆
There's cold bread and molasses.
我吃过牡蛎了 妈
I had the oysters,Ma.
这个你肯定没有
Well,here's something you don't have.
有人要扔了它
Someone was throwing it away.
里面全是好玩的东西
It's full of interesting things.
你的那位先生 今天又玩老把戏了 对吧
Your man was up to his tricks today,wasn't he?
您说谁
Sir?
那个准将
Your Commodore.
口袋里全是金币的那位
With his pockets full of gold.
他开放大海了
He opened the sea.
现在连大海都属于他了吗
Does he own that,too,now?
只对城里的人开放
Just for the city people.
把金子扔到水里
Gold in the water.
你们这些小鱼儿抢来抢去
All the little fishies biting.
快吃
Go on.
你抓到什么了
So what did you catch, hmm?
抓到金子了吗 小鱼儿
You catch some gold, little fish?
没有
No, sir.
为什么没有
Why not?
我不够快
I wasn't quick enough.
我的靴子晾在门口了 去看看
My boots is drying on the porch. Go check them.
你妈妈折腾了三天才生下你
It took your mother three days to birth you.
我当时在出海
I was out on the water.
我不知道自己会成为父亲还是鳏夫
I didn't know if I was a father or a widower.
我回到家时 她披着头发躺在床上
I come home, she was in bed with her hair down.
她一头美丽的头发
Her beautiful hair.
怀里抱着一个男婴
A boy in her arms.
我儿子
My boy.
你的父亲是个渔夫
You're the son of a fisherman.
你还想抓什么啊
And what are you trying to catch?
吃完
Finish that.
那家伙究竟在哪
Where goddamn hell is this guy?
是你请的议员
He's your senator.
三个小时的车程
It's a three-hour drive.
在这就没有准时开始的事情
Nothing happens on time here.
我所担心的不是古巴时间
It's not the clocks in Cuba I'm worried about.
孩子 先别说话
Hey, kid, please.
给你这个
Here, you take 'em.
我会为您提供最好的服务
I give you the good ones.
我的幸运数字
That's my lucky number.
罗伊德说了 他们需要收益
You heard Lloyd. They need the revenue.
希望投票结果出来时 一切都已经安排妥当了
I want everything set up and ready the day the vote comes down
我就可以第一时间赶去
so I can be in there first.
你去了又能怎样
Let's say you are.
无论别人怎么想 觉得我干过什么事
Then, whatever anyone thinks, whatever they claim I've done,
我都是清白的
I'm clean.
怎么了
What?
那边发生了什么事
What is going on over there?
-他们在喊什么 -反对马查多之类的
-What are they saying? -Anti-Machado stuff.
时任古巴总统 古巴独立战争将军
又是精彩的一天
Another day in paradise.
这些人总喜欢抱怨一些事情
Always complaining about something.
以后可能就不止是抱怨了
Might wind up doing more than that.
迈耶
Meyer.
纳吉 你好
Nucky. Hello.
维特小姐
And Miss Wheet.
有段时间没见了
Been a while.
Ar葬礼之后就没见了
A.R.'s funeral.
悲恸的一天
A sad day.
-愿他安息 -你来这做什么
-Rest his soul. -What brings you here?
来这陪我妻子度假
Wife's been hocking me for a holiday.
-结婚了 -是的
-Married? -Married.
有个儿子 使我开始为未来做打算
A son. Makes you concentrate on the future.
-我们应该... -是的
-We should all---We should.
迈耶
Meyer.
替我向查理问好
My best to Charlie.
我们没怎么联系过
We don't talk too often.
我们俩还有人是单身汉
One of us is still a bachelor.
他来这做什么
What's his story?
来这度假
Man on vacation.
跟你一样
Just like you.
早啊 两位
Morning, folks.
现在还是早上 不是吗
It is still morning, isn't it?
温德尔 你去哪了
Wendell, where have you been?
说实话 我也不是很清楚
Tell the truth, I wasn't exactly sure.
我还记得上次
I remember that last time.
-我们当时也在 -他可是聚会的主心骨
-We were there. -He was the life of the party.
-是吗 -可不是
-I don't know. -Right you are.
过来 快过来
Come on. Come on.
过去点
Move over.
我没位置了
Come on, I don't have enough space.
-还有空地 -没有了
-Yes, you do. -No.
-你挤着我了 -空间明明足够大
-You're crowding me. -There's room enough.
-别闹 -走开
-Stop. -Get away.
别闹好吗 吉姆
Play fair, why don't you, Jim?
我可没闹
I ain't playing.
-他们来了 -快点
-Here they come. -Shh. Come on.
快上 快上
Come on! Come on! Come on!
-这里有一顶 -那个归我
-There's one over there! -I got that one!
快点 快点
Come on! Come on!
-又有一顶 -我拿到一顶
-Oh, I got another one! -I got one!
拿到第二顶
Yes, I got a second one!
谢谢你 给你
Thank you. Here, for you.
我捡到你帽子了 先生
Got your skimmers, misters.
真厉害 有蓝带子的是我的
Can you beat that? The blue band's mine.
-这里这顶是我的 -真好看
-That one's mine right there. -It's a fine one.
先生 这是你的吗
Sir, is this yours?
给他点钱 杰克
Give him something, Jake.
10美分就可以 先生
10 cents will do it, sir.
你这个小强盗
You little pirate.
-这是你的吗 -我的呢
-Is this yours? -Hey, where's mine?
给你 小子
Here. Here you go, son.
-在哪呢 -谢谢你
-Where is it? -Thank you so much.
-谢谢 谢谢 -他来了
-Thank you. Thank you. -Here he comes.
-很好 -谢谢
-Very nice. -Thank you.
给你20美分
20 cents.
我没抢到
I don't have it.
再找找
Go look.
你在指望大风把帽子刮来吗
You just hide here and pray for wind?
不是 通常是下午才起风
No, it generally blows up in the afternoon.
拿个尝尝
Take one.
拿两个吧
Hell, take two.
派特 你来吗
Hey, Pat. Are you coming?
向乡村乐园前进
Onward to rustic pleasures!
好了 继续出发吧
All right, here we go.
我跟你比赛到码头
Come on, I'll race you to the pier.
等你们回来的路上再见
Bye! See you on the way back!
再见
Good-bye.
再使点劲 再使点劲
Work it up. Work it up. Work it up, now.
加把劲
Put your back in it.
搞定一个 霍斯 还有一百个
That one down, Hoss. 100 to go.
米尔顿 我还不知道你能数到一百呢
I didn't know you could count that high, Milton.
十根手指 十根脚趾
10 fingers, 10 toes.
那是多少
How much that is?
不用担心
Don't worry yourself.
能给我点水喝吗
Some water maybe?
拎过来水桶
Bucket.
来了 霍斯
Coming up, Hoss.
继续干活
Back in it!
你头上的疤是怎么回事
How'd you get that dent in your head?
霍斯 我九岁时 爸爸对我说
Well, Hoss, I wasn't but nine and Pappy say,
"米尔顿 知道这是什么吗
"Milton, you know what that is?
这是头倒着的驴
That's an ass backwards.
这头驴总是反着来做事情"
Ass like that do everything in reverse."
我跑过去骑那头驴
So I go to ride him.
沿着驴屁股爬上去 开始倒着骑驴
Climb up on that rump, facing the south side.
拽着它的毛尾巴 大喊"好耶"
Grab hold of that bushy tail, yell, "Geeyup!"
结果那头驴像扔棒球一样把我甩了出去
Whoo, and that mule tossed me like a baseball on Sunday.
就是这样 祝您心情愉快
Yes, sir. Happy day.
没水了
Ain't none left.
系好靴子
Tie that boot.
快点干活
Work it up.
快点干活 快点干活
Work it up. Work it up. Work it up.
开始干活了
Let's go, now!
你吃牡蛎了
You ate oysters.
听谁说的
Says who?
吃了吗
Did you?
我看到你在那了
I can see you there.
跟一群有钱人在一起 好像你也是有钱人
With all the swells. Like you belonged.
他们跟普通人没多大区别
They're not so special.
就是有钱
All they have is money.
还有赚钱的法子 这点我承认
Ways to find that, I reckon.
怎么赚钱
How?
先到先得
Get yourself there first.
苏 把手给我
Give me your hand, Sue.
好酸
Sour.
我喜欢
I like it.
先生 有什么需要效劳的吗
Signore, how may I please you?
布鲁克林 康尼岛
离门越远越好
Furthest from the door.
罗翰小姐 他想见你
Miss Rohan. He wants to see you.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
什么
Sir?
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
我很震惊
I... shocked?
还很伤心
And saddened.
-焦虑  -我们都很焦虑
-Concerned. -We are all concerned.
所有人都非常焦虑
All very concerned.
你为班尼特先生主要做什么事
What did you do for Mr. Bennett?
管理他的日程安排
Managed his appointments.
把外贸订单归档
Made sure trade orders were promptly filed.
就这些吗
That's all?
有时会为班尼特夫人跑跑腿
I sometimes ran errands for Mrs. Bennett.
买买东西什么的
Shopping and the like.
班尼特先生告诉我秘书
Mr. Bennett assured me secretaries were expected
就是要做这些事
to carry out duties of that nature.
有什么不对的地方吗
Was that improper?
我在这位子上已经四十年了
I've been at this 40 years.
大风大浪都见过
Boom and bust.
只要别迷失自己
You can always make money on the street
你总会赚到钱的
as long as you don't get yourself turned around.
千万别迷失自己
Don't get turned around.
还没结婚吧
Not married?
还没有 康纳先生
No, Mr. Conors.
还有什么家人
Family?
有个哥哥和几个姐妹
Brother and sisters.
是时候该找个丈夫了
Time you found a husband.
您是要解雇我吗
Am I to be let go?
你知道他把办公室里
Do you know where he kept the key
文件柜的钥匙放在哪里吗
to the file cabinet in his office?
不知道
No.
我们要打开那个文件柜
We need to open the file cabinet.
但我不知道钥匙放在哪
I don't know where he kept it.
找个锁匠
Call a locksmith.
把柜子撬开
Have him open it.
我有问过你感觉怎么样吗
Did I ask how you feel?
问过了
You did.
那就好
Good.
谢了 哥们
Thank you, brother.
你在干什么
What you doing now?
补靴子吗
Fixing up that boot, huh?
是的 你很聪明啊
Yeah, that's smart.
脚不舒服 做什么都费劲
Feet ain't right, everything go slipways. Yes, sir.
看我这双 我从厨子那偷了点牛油
These here? I sneak some grease off from the cook.
把脚擦一遍 很舒服
Rub it all in, keep it real soft.
虽然破了个洞 但没多大妨碍
Hole right here, though. That ain't much.
你就从来都不想说点什么吗
Don't you never want to say nothing?
你是做了什么而被抓进来的
What you done in the first place?
反正是被抓了
Got myself caught.
你可真会编故事
You sure do weave a tale.
我杀了自己的爸爸
I stove my pappy's head in is what.
他每天虐待我 我实在是忍不了了
'Cause I wouldn't stand for them tricks he pulled on me no more.
没错
Yes, sir.
好样的
Hog eye!
去干活 去干活 去干活
Work it up. Work it up. Work it up.
去干活了 犯人
Let's go, Stripey.
我说了去干活
I said let's go.
你每次但是速度最慢的
Always the last one sitting.
-你们都是工人  -我会好好教训你
-This is a work crew. -I'll give you some, boy.
你如果不想干了 就关禁闭
If you don't like the work, there's the box.
我不管 我不管
I don't care! I don't care!
你们这些混蛋
Fuck every motherfucking one of y'all.
起来啊 杂种
Get up, mutt!
你用过电话吗
You ever talk on a telephone?
用过电话吗
You ever talk on one?
那个盒子就那么大点
How they fit a body's voice
是怎么可以用来说话的
inside that little box?
通电
Electricity.
钱就在瑟蒙特外的一栋房里
Money in a house outside Thurmont.
我们平分
Split it with you.
打电话什么的你来做
You handle all the telephones and such.
唐 法昆从加泰罗尼亚来到这
Don Facundo came here from Catalonia.
在那之前根本没有好喝的酒
Before that, there was nothing worth drinking.
但现在 一想到古巴
But today, when you think of Cuba,
就会想到朗姆酒
you think of rum.
一想到朗姆酒...
When you think of rum--
你是怎么得到公司的 罗尼斯先生
How did you wind up running the company, Mr. Ronis?
我娶了老板的女儿
Married the boss's daughter.
幸运的姑娘
Well, lucky girl.
谢谢 惠特小姐
Très gentille, Miss Wheet.
你主营市场在哪
And your market?
拉丁美洲和欧洲
Latin America. Europe.
下个月我们要在墨西哥开家工厂
Next month we open a plant in Mexico.
你好像还少点什么
Sounds like something's missing.
这已经不是秘密了
It is no secret.
我们想让百加得重新进军美国市场
We would like Bacardi again for sale in the States.
我愿意做代理
And I'd like to be the man to sell it.
但法律不允许
Not possible, though. Legally.
现在是不行 但局势要变了
Not today. But that's going to change.
是这样吗 劳埃德参议员
Is it so, Senator Lloyd?
美国这条船很强大
Well, America is a mighty vessel, sir.
-转向它不容易 -然而...
-It's not easily turned. -However...
国家的政治资本
The political capital needed to
需要这样的转变...
effect a change of such sweeping--
无论怎样 你的观点是...
However, your informed opinion...
-我记不太清了 -你当然记得很清楚
-I don't recall precisely-- -Of course you do.
你 我 萨利都在场
It was you, me, Sally,
还有一位小姐叫什么来着
and what was the senorita's name?
她听得很认真
She was paying particularly close attention.
朋友间之间的私密谈话
Speaking privately among friends,
美国那边已经准备好前进了
the country is ready to move forward.
这是个很好的机会
And that is an opportunity.
唐 马克西姆 我有个在待命的销售网
Don Maxime, I have a distribution network already in place.
在佛罗里达海岸的深水港
Deepwater port on the Florida coast.
还有跟铁路局和货运公司达成的协议
Agreements with rail lines and trucking companies.
禁酒令一解除 我意欲以合法方式
The day repeal passes, I intend to be open for business legally
在全球需求最高的国家打开市场
in the thirstiest country on Earth
独家销售百加得朗姆酒
with Bacardi Rum as my most exclusive offering.
我们能合作吗
Can the two of us come to an arrangement?
有保镖吗
A bodyguard?
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
没有 我自己有几个保镖
No. I have several myself.
古巴如今可不安全
Cuba today is not so safe.
那就在墨西哥建工厂
So build a plant in Mexico.
留条后路总是好的
Well, it's always wise to have an exit arranged.
您这种人
A man like yourself
最明白吧
would understand that.
亚伯 利德斯通
Redatone, A.
我找到钥匙了
I found the key.
我16岁来这
I come, 16 year old.
什么都没有
I don't got nothing.
什么也不奢求
Don't ask for nothing.
你白手起家的 乔
You pulled yourself up, Joe.
我得奋斗
I have to fight.
我没得选
What choice they give me?
每天都要打一架
Every day a fight.
但只有一个人能当老大
But one man, one boss.
别无选择
I don't work no other way.
马拉暂罗也是这么想的(黑手党头目)
Maranzano's got the same idea.
去他的
他把我们当傻子糊弄
He's playing us for saps.
不能坐享别人的成果
You don't take what someone else build.
马拉暂罗去他的吧
Maranzano,fuck him.
我呢
And me...
没人能跟我斗
Nobody fucks with me.
没人
Nobody.
明白吗
Understand?
给句话 来个了结
So give me the word and we'll end it.
你把我的麻烦都解决吗
You fix all my trouble, huh?
-也是我的麻烦 -那你要怎么办
-It's my trouble, too. -And what do you do, then, huh?
解决完后打算干什么
After you fix?
为什么要这么问
Why do you have to say that?
我不忠诚吗
Ain't I been loyal?
一直以来 我都跟你混
All this time, I stuck with you.
支持你
I'm here with you.
同生共死
Same blood.
你怎么处理
How you take care of it?
那是我的事
Just leave that to me.
你不知道 也就不受牵连
What you don't know, you can't get nailed for.
乔
Joe.
你还打算失去多少
How much more you want to lose?
老大只一个
One boss.
要在这坐一整天吗
We gonna sit here all day?
你要去哪吗
Where you got to go?
撒泡尿 喝了五杯了
The head. Five espresso.
想干什么就去吧
Do what you need to.
还好吗 老板
How you doing, boss?
查理在吗
Charlie here?
-怎么这么慢  -堵了一路
-What the fuck took so long? -Traffic the whole way.
必须要解决他 对吧
Had to be done, right?
你的奋斗结束了
The fight is over.
沃特 沃特 慢点孩子
I say, Walt. Walt. Not so fast, my boy.
闪开 闪开
Get! Go on!
男人总要时不时地出去一趟
A man needs to get out of town every now and then.
这只是个冠冕堂皇的理由
That's just the glory of the whole proposition.
布鲁克林也有海滩的
They have beaches in Brooklyn.
时机正好 帕特 你看不出来吗
Right opportunity, Pat. Can't you see it?
那你自己怎么不做
Then why don't you do it yourself?
我需要纽约投资
I need the New York money.
想想吧 横跨新泽西州的铁路
Just think, rail line straight down from the Jersey crossing.
停在哪 你家门前吗
Stopping where? On your doorstep?
我关心的是大西洋城
It's Atlantic City I care about.
我要在这大干一番
I aim to build something great here
跟我一起干的人
and those who join with me--
-我警告过你了  -没有
-You was warned once. -No, I wasn't.
你们这群码头上的老鼠
Bunch of wharf rats, the lot of you.
快滚蛋 走吧
Clear out, now. Let's go.
怎么了 雅各布
What's the ruckus, Jacob?
我告诉他们别聚堆
I told them no congregating.
要听治安官的话 孩子
Sheriff's meant to be obeyed, boy.
这是他的
This is his.
是吗
Well?
给你了
Here you go.
先生
Sir?
你不是找到我的帽子了吗
Found my hat, didn't you?
太多了
It's too much.
跟什么比
Compared to what?
你知道帽子里有钱吗
Did you know that money was there?
知道
Yes, sir.
那为什么不拿
Then why didn't you take it?
说实话
Answer true.
能够出人头地
To get myself ahead.
别让小孩子围在门口
No boys on the porch.
滚蛋
Scram.
查理 帮我扶梯子
Charlie, steady this ladder for me.
好了 扶住了
All right. Hold on.
行了吗
That good for you?
洗漱一下 来酒吧
Freshen up. Come down to the bar.
好多崇拜者等着你呢
You'll have lots of admirers waiting.
你可真能使唤人
You're quite a slave driver.
给你说清楚 免得你再走丢了
Pin a note on you this time so you don't get lost.
我的天
Well, oh, my.
能谈一下吗
Can we talk for a moment?
-我得买烟  -里面见了
-I need to get cigarettes. -See you boys inside.
先说明白
Let's get something straight.
我不是你的手下
I'm not your whipping boy.
也不是来这任别人差遣的
And I'm not here to get tarred with someone else's brush.
不管禁酒法案怎么样
Whatever happens with volstead,
-不管咱们两个怎么样... -一包好彩
-whatever happens between us... -Lucky strikes.
法案的事我可不敢打包票
...I won't make guarantees about legislation,
没人能
nobody can--
我可不想被人反咬一口
I won't get bitten in the ass.
你在听我说吗
Are you listening to me?
我已经买的那些怎么办呢
What happened to the ones I already bought?
都是垃圾
Those were shit.
这号码明天能中奖
I give you good number for tomorrow.
这位子我坐了20年了
I've had that seat for 20 years.
就一晚逛窑子...
and one night in some dago cathouse...
一整本多少钱
How much for the whole book?
你也不可以这样对我...
doesn't buy you the right to treat me...
...把我当参议院小听差使唤
...like some kind of senate page boy.
-先交货 -你以为
-You first. -You think you're the
只有你在求我吗
only one who comes knocking on my door?
看到没 生意就是这么做的
See? This is how we do business.
身家比你干净的人多了
There are plenty of fellas with cleaner fingernails than you.
先生 小心
Socio, watch out!
小心
Watch out!
给你
There you go.
纽约 布朗克斯
朋友们 朋友们
Amici. Amici.
我们来这庆祝什么
What do we come to celebrate?
乔 马塞里亚蛋蛋中了20枪
20 pills in Joe Masseria's gut.
干杯
Salute!
分久必合
Kingdoms rise,
合久必分
kingdoms fall.
冒牌货虽然能接近帝位
Pretenders reach for the throne,
可只有凯撒能做皇帝
but only Caesar can rule.
冒牌货都会被忘却
And the pretenders fade away.
这代表着什么
What does it all mean?
用马可 奥勒留(罗马皇帝)的话说
In the words of marcus aurelius,
"宇宙变幻无常
"the universe is change.
我们的生活由自己的想法决定"
our life is what our thoughts make it."
而我的想法
And my thoughts
就在这
are these.
在座的每一位
Everybody in this room...
都要暴富了
is going to get rich!
今晚来了位新朋友
A new friend is here tonight.
西西里的后代
A son of Sicily.
美国的后代
A son of America.
我们欠他许多
We owe him much.
来吧
Come forward.
让他过来
Let him through. -
英雄
The hero.
唐 塞尔瓦托
Don Salvatore.
致我们
To us
在座的各位
And only us.
生生不息
Now and forever.
他说 他说这群人
He says--he says these people
是贼 罪犯
Are thieves, criminals.
古巴的敌人
Enemies of Cuba.
总想空手套白狼
They want something for nothing.
他们偷 抢
They steal, they rob.
街上有钱的美国人就是他们的商机
A rich American on the street, an opportunity.
他说要处理这件事
He says there are formalities
还需要些手续
concerning the incident.
多少钱
How much
能封口
to keep it quiet?
两百
200.
大伙 他们来了
Hey, fellas, they're here.
-快走 -快走
-Let's go! -Let's go!
-别挡道 -你闪开
-Move out of my way! -No, you. Beat it.
-我来  -女士
-Me! Me! -Hey, lady!
-需要帮忙拎包吗 -我们是来帮忙的 女士
-Help you with your bags? -We're here to help, ma'am.
-需要帮忙吗 -可别让沙子
-May I help you? -Don't want to
溜进您漂亮的凉鞋里
get sand in your pretty slippers.
抓住我的手 女士 我来帮你
Take my hand, ma'am. I'll help you.
是我帮你吧
I should be helping you.
我来吧 女士 小心点
I've got you, ma'am. Watch your step.
这就对了
There you go.
-欢迎来到大西洋城 -你真是绅士
-Welcome to Atlantic City. -You're quite the gentleman.
谢谢你 小伙子
Thank you, young man.
给你
Here you are.
-你跟她真像  -他屁股更大
-You look just like her. -No, his butt is bigger.
是啊
Yes.
放开
Get off.
揍他 快揍他...
Get him! Beat him! Get him! Get him!
-住手 -这不公平
-Stop it! -Ain't fair!
-别打了 小伙子们  -不公平
-Boys, stop doing that. -Ain't fair!
不公平
Ain't fair.
派尼连打架都不敢
Piney can't fight worth a damn.
让他们打
Let them fight.
走吧
Let's go.
你是谁家孩子
Whose boy are you?
伊桑 汤普森家的
Ethan Thompson's.
水手伊桑啊
Ethan the bay man.
你认识吗
You know him?
你觉得自己之前挺聪明吗
Thought you were being clever before, hmm?
觉得自己挺诚实的 该得点奖赏吗
Thought you were gonna get something for being honest.
你得到什么了
What have you got?
一切事都要通过我 明白吗
Everything goes through me, understand?
不论大小
Big and little.
从阿布西肯湾到巨蛋湾
Absecon Inlet to Great Egg Harbor.
任何差错都会对对生意不利
Anything else is bad for business.
这里
Here...
有沙子
is sand.
那边有扫帚
There is a broom.
这个...
And this...
是一美元
is one dollar.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
欢迎来到大西洋城
Welcome to Atlantic City!
这里有雨伞 毛毯...
We got umbrellas, blankets...
你见他割耳朵了吗
You saw what he did with the ear?
还在他兜里吗
Is it still in his pocket?
这事不要告诉罗尼斯为好
Ronis doesn't need to hear about any of this.
只需要告诉他 什么都没发生
As far as he's concerned, nothing's happened
劳埃德还同意合作
and Lloyd's still on board.
别指望他
Well, don't count on it.
又不是只有你打点军队了
You're not the only one who pays off the army.
有像我这样的吗
A man like me?
纠结过去有什么意思
Where's the sense in looking back?
没什么好处
Never does any good.
"要诚实真诚 孩子们"
"Be honest and true, boys."
什么
What's that?
突然想到而已
Just running through my head.
回房间吧
Come up to the room.
我明天就坐船走了
I'm on the clipper out tomorrow.
-没事 -不能让你一个人
-That's all right. -No night to be alone.
亲爱的 我不是一个人
Sweetie, I'm not alone.
也不全是坏消息嘛
Not all bad news.
还赢了五比索
Won five pesos.
兰斯基夫人
Mrs. Lansky.
我是您丈夫的一个老朋友
I'm an old friend of your husband's.
你是在等他吗
Are you waiting for him to join you?
你会讲英语吗
Do you speak English?
会
I speak, yes.
你有丈夫吗
You have a husband?
你可以做我丈夫
You can be my husband.
一晚 一周
One night, one week.
找个角落 我肯定让你爽
We go around the corner, I'll make you feel good.
至真至善之人 总是弥足珍贵
"The best and the truest; Alas! Are the fewest;
努力做这样的人
But be one of these if you can.
尽职尽责
In duty, ne'er fail;
这会让你受益匪浅
You will find 'twill avail you,
终生受用
And bring its reward when a man.
生活的海洋充满波浪...
Don't think life plain sailing,
充满艰险
there's danger of failing,
尽管未来貌似光明...
though bright the futures seem to be...
但尊严 努力 真诚待人
but bright honor and labor and truth to your neighbor
会带你平安度过人生之海
will bear you safe over life's seas.
奋起直追  坚持梦想
Then up and be doing, right only pursuing,
去尽力奋斗
and take your fair part in the strife.
做人要诚实 孩子们
Be honesty and true, boys!
凡事都要真诚 孩子们
Whatever you do, boys,
要铭记一生
Let this be your motto through life!"